<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_driver_map">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_controll_data">ControllDataActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pressure_data">PressureDataActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_driver_mode">DriverMode</string>


    <string name="VinCommand">Vehicle Identification Number (VIN)</string>

    <string name="ModuleVoltageCommand">Control module voltage is the voltage supplied to the ECU.\n
  It isn\'t battery voltage but is usually close enough when the vehicle is running.\n
 </string>

    <string name="TimingAdvanceCommand">Timing Advance
    It refers to the spark igniting the air-fuel mixture in the cylinder in relation
      to the piston position in crankshaft degrees.\n The timing of the spark must change
      with engine conditions for the engine to run efficiently.\n
     </string>

    <string name="EquivalentRatioCommand">

  Fuel systems that use conventional oxygen sensor display the commanded open
  loop equivalence ratio while the system is in open loop.\n Should report 100%
  when in closed loop fuel.\n
  To obtain the actual air/fuel ratio being commanded, multiply the
  stoichiometric A/F ratio by the equivalence ratio.\n For example, gasoline
  stoichiometric is 14.64:1 ratio.\n If the fuel control system was commande an
  equivalence ratio of 0.\n95, the commanded A/F ratio to the engine would be
  14.64 * 0.95 = 13.9 A/F.\n

    </string>

    <string name="DistanceMILOnCommand"> Distance traveled with malfunction indicator lamp (MIL) on
</string>

    <string name="TimeRunWithMILOnCommand">TimeRunWithMILOnCommand</string>

    <string name="DistanceSinceCCCommand">  Distance traveled since codes cleared-up.\n
</string>

    <string name="TimeSinceTroubleCodesClearedCommand">TimeSinceTroubleCodesClearedCommand</string>

    <string name="AbsoluteLoadCommand">LOAD_ABS = [air mass (g / intake stroke)] / [1.184 (g / intake stroke) ""
 cylinder displacement in liters]
 Where:
 - STP = Standard Temperature and Pressure = 25 °C, 29.92 in Hg (101.3 kPa)
 BARO
 - WOT = wide open throttle

  As you can probably see, this equation relies on the flow of air and basically engine displacement.\n
  As it states in the body, this correlates with volumetric efficiency (how completely a cylinder fills with
  air on the intake stroke) at WOT.\n This variable can be read from the ECU on PID $43.\n It is only required
  by the standard on spark ignition systems.\n
 </string>

<string name="FuelInjectionTimingCommand">FuelInjectionTimingCommand</string>

    <string name="LoadCommand">  Calculated Engine Load value.\n
 
  According to SAE International SAE J1979 / ISO 15031-5
 (dated: 2014-08-11), calculated engine load is calculated by the following equation
  Where:
 - STP = Standard Temperature and Pressure = 25 °C, 29.92 in Hg BARO,
 - SQRT = square root
 - WOT = wide open throttle
 - AAT = Ambient Air Temperature (in °C)
 
  There isn\'t a single sensor it uses to figure this out.\n For a gasoline (or spark ignition) engine,
  it utilizes the Air Intake Sensor (IAT), Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP)
  sensor, Throttle Position Sensor (TPS), and Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor
  to do calculations and to discover if the engine is at the ready point to make the calculations.\n
 
 </string>
  <string name="MassAirFlowCommand"> Mass Air Flow (MAF)
 
  (MAF) is a sensor used to determine the mass flow rate of air entering a fuel-injected internal combustion engine.\n
  The air mass information is necessary for the engine control unit (ECU)
  to balance and deliver the correct fuel mass to the engine.\n Air changes its density with temperature
  and pressure.\n In automotive applications, air density varies with the ambient temperature, altitude and the use
  of forced induction, which means that mass flow sensors are more appropriate
  than volumetric flow sensors for determining the quantity of intake air in each cylinder</string>

    <string name="OilTempCommand">  Displays the current engine Oil temperature.\n
</string>

    <string name="RelativeAcceleratorPedalPositionCommand">RelativeAcceleratorPedalPositionCommand</string>

    <string name="RPMCommand">  Displays the current engine revolutions per minute (RPM).\n
</string>


    <string name="RuntimeCommand">  Engine runtime.\n
 
  Run time since engine start
</string>

    <string name="ThrottlePositionCommand"> Read the throttle position in percentage.\n
  what is a throttle ?
  a device controlling the flow of fuel or power to an engine.\n
</string>


    <string name="AirFuelRatioCommand">AirFuelRatioCommand</string>

    <string name="ConsumptionRateCommand">ConsumptionRateCommand</string>

    <string name="FindFuelTypeCommand">  This command is intended to determine the vehicle fuel type.\n
</string>

    <string name="FuelLevelCommand">  Get fuel level in percentage
</string>

    <string name="FuelTrimCommand"> Select one of the Fuel Trim percentage banks to access.\n
 fuel trims are the percentage of change in fuel over time.\n
  For the engine to operate properly, the air:fuel ratio needs to stay within a small window of 14.7:1.\n
 
 
 If the o2 sensors inform the engine computer that the exhaust mixture is lean, the
  computer adds fuel by lengthening injector pulse, or "on-time", to compensate.\n
  Conversely, if the o2 sensors inform the computer that the exhaust is rich,
  the computer shortens injector pulse, adding less fuel to compensate in order to bring
  the rich condition down.\n
 
 
  This change in fuel being added or taken away is called Fuel Trim.\n
  Really, the oxygen sensors are what drive the fuel trim readings.\n Changes in o2 sensor voltages cause
  a direct change in fuel.\n The short term fuel trim (STFT) refers to immediate changes in fuel occurring
  several times per second.\n The long term fuel trims (LTFT) are driven by the short term fuel trims.\n
  LTFT refers to changes in STFT but averaged over a longer period of time.\n
  A negative fuel trim percentage indicates a taking away of fuel while a
  positive percentage indicates an adding of fuel</string>

    <string name="WidebandAirFuelRatioCommand"> Oxygen sensors are usually located in the exhaust manifolds or exhaust piping.\n
  They read data from the exhaust gasses leaving the engine.\n
  This is helpful in determining if the engine is running correctly.\n
  However, if you are trying to determine the AFR entering the engine,
  which is what it sounds like, the oxygen sensors would not be very helpful.\n
  A very high or very low reading could indicate that the intake AFR is not correct,
  but getting an actual number would be difficult.\n
 </string>

    <string name="AbsoluteEvapSystemVaporPressureCommand">AbsoluteEvapSystemVaporPressureCommand</string>

    <string name="BarometricPressureCommand">
  The barometric (BARO) sensor is used by the engine control module (ECM)
  to measure the pressure of the atmosphere.\n The pressure is affected
  by weather conditions, air volume, and altitude.\n
 </string>

    <string name="EvapSystemVaporPressureCommand">EvapSystemVaporPressureCommand</string>

    <string name="FuelPressureCommand"> On a car with fuel injection there can be two fuel pumps,
  one high-pressure and one low-pressure.\n
  The low-pressure pump moves the gas from the tank up to the
  high pressure pump.\n The high pressure pump then raises the pressure to a
  level that will be useful to the injectors.\n
  The two PIDs reflect those two different systems.\n
  PID  Description        Min       Max      Units
  0A   Fuel pressure        0       765      kPa (gauge)
  22   Fuel rail pressure   0     5,177.265  kPa
  23   Fuel rail pressure   0   655,350      kPa
 
 
  These pressures are all controlled by regulators so that any of these PIDs should be fairly
  constant and not affected by load in a well running engine.\n
  Low fuel pressure would be the result of failure or clog in the fuel system.\n
 </string>

    <string name="FuelRailPressureCommand">
   On a car with fuel injection there can be two fuel pumps,
  one high-pressure and one low-pressure.\n
  The low-pressure pump moves the gas from the tank up to the
  high pressure pump.\n The high pressure pump then raises the pressure to a
  level that will be useful to the injectors.\n
  The two PIDs reflect those two different systems.\n
  PID  Description        Min       Max      Units
  0A   Fuel pressure        0       765      kPa (gauge)
  22   Fuel rail pressure   0     5,177.265  kPa
  23   Fuel rail pressure   0   655,350      kPa
 
 
  These pressures are all controlled by regulators so that any of these PIDs should be fairly
  constant and not affected by load in a well running engine.\n
  Low fuel pressure would be the result of failure or clog in the fuel system.\n
 </string>

    <string name="IntakeManifoldPressureCommand">The Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor is a key sensor because it senses engine load.\n
  The sensor generates a signal that is proportional to the amount of vacuum in the intake manifold.\n
  The engine computer then uses this information to adjust ignition timing and fuel enrichment.\n
 
  When the engine is working hard, intake vacuum drops as the throttle opens wide.\n
  The engine sucks in more air, which requires more fuel to keep the air/fuel ratio in balance.\n
  In fact, when the computer reads a heavy load signal from the MAP sensor,
  it usually makes the fuel mixture go slightly richer than normal so the engine can produce more power.\n
  At the same time, the computer will retard (back off) ignition timing slightly to prevent detonation (spark knock)
  that can damage the engine and hurt performance.\n
 
  When conditions change and the vehicle is cruising along under light load, coasting or decelerating,
  less power is needed from the engine.\n The throttle is not open very wide or may be closed causing
  intake vacuum to increase.\n The MAP sensor senses this and the computer responds by leaning out the
  fuel mixture to reduce fuel consumption and advances ignition timing to squeeze a little
  more fuel economy out of the engine.\n
 
 
  An intake manifold is a component that delivers either air or an air/fuel mixture to the cylinders
  In fuel-injected engines, the intake manifold connects the throttle body to the intake ports.\n
 
  In addition to simply providing a path for air or air and fuel to move between a common
  intake and the intake ports, intake manifolds also perform another important function.\n Due to the way that internal
  combustion engines work, and the way that intake manifolds are “sealed” by the constant flow of air in one side and out the
  other, the movement of the pistons in the engine is able to effectively create a partial vacuum inside the intake manifold.\n
  When each piston moves downward on the intake stroke, it sucks air (or air and fuel) out of the intake manifold.\n
  This creates a situation where the pressure inside the manifold is lower than the pressure outside of the manifold,
  which results in a partial vacuum.\n This vacuum is then harnessed to perform a variety of different functions that
  range all the way from climate controls to brake boosters.\n
 
 
  Since manifold vacuum is produced by the normal operation of the engine, the level of vacuum can
  also be used to diagnose certain engine problems.\n For instance, low vacuum might indicate a burnt valve,
  incorrect valve or ignition timing, or a variety of other problems.\n
 </string>

    <string name="AirIntakeTemperatureCommand">The Intake Air Temperature sensor (IAT) monitors the temperature
  of the air entering the engine.\n The engine computer (PCM) needs this information to estimate
  air density so it can balance  air/fuel mixture.\n Colder air is more dense than hot air,
  so cold air requires more fuel to maintain the same air/fuel ratio.\n The PCM changes the air/fuel ratio
  by changing the length (on time) of the injector pulses.\n
 </string>

    <string name="AmbientAirTemperatureCommand">
  Ambient Air Temperature
 
  The Ambient Air Temperature (AAT) sensor converts ambient air temperature into
  an electrical signal for the Powertrain Control Module (PCM).\n This input is used to modify air
  conditioning system operation and display outside air temperature.\n
 
  The PCM receives this input and possibly two more; Intake Air Temperature (IAT) and Engine Coolant
  Temperature Sensor (ECT).\n The PCM looks at the AAT sensor voltage and compares it to the IAT/ECT
  sensor readings when the ignition switch is first turned on after a long cool down period.\n
  This code is set if these inputs vary too much.\n It also looks at the voltage signals from these
  sensors to determine if they are correct when the engine is fully warmed up.\n This code is usually
  set due to electrical issues, but mechanical faults should not be dismissed.\n These mechanical issues
  would include improper mounting location of the sensor, not mounting the sensor
  (leaving it hanging by the wiring harness), etc.\n
 </string>

    <string name="CatalystTemperatureCommand">CatalystTemperatureCommand</string>
    
    <string name="EngineCoolantTemperatureCommand"> Engine Coolant Temperature.\n
  Engine Coolant Temperature Sensor is a sensor that is screwed into the engine\'s
  block or cylinder head and is used to determine the temperature of the engine coolant.\n
  reading is sent to the vehicle\'s PCM/ECM (car\'s onboard computer) and is or can be used to
  activate emission controls or turn the engine\'s cooling fan on.\n
 </string>
    
    <string name="DtcNumberCommand"> This command will for now read MIL (check engine light) state and number of
  diagnostic trouble codes currently flagged in the ECU.\n
  Perhaps in the future we\'ll extend this to read the 3rd, 4th and 5th bytes of
  the response in order to store information about the availability and
  completeness of certain on-board tests.\n</string>
    <string name="PendingTroubleCodesCommand">what is pending DTCs ??
      The computer detects something "wrong", but the error usually has to be present after a
      few driving cycles before it turns into an "actual" code that triggers the Check Engine Light.\n
      Otherwise, if the code goes away before that, then the computer shrugs it off.\n</string>
    
    <string name="PermanentTroubleCodesCommand">Mode $0A—Request emissions-related diagnostic trouble codes with permanent status after a
      clear/reset emission-related diagnostic information service.\n The purpose of mode $0A,
      referred to as Mode 10, is to allow a scan tool to obtain DTCs that are stored as
      “permanent codes.\n” These are codes only the module can clear.\n Even if you’ve made
      a successful repair and have cleared the codes in Mode $04, these codes will
      remain in memory until the computer has completed its own system test.\n</string>
    
    <string name="TroubleCodesCommand"> what is pending DTCs ??
      The computer detects something "wrong", but the error usually has to be present after a
      few driving cycles before it turns into an "actual" code that triggers the Check Engine Light.\n
      Otherwise, if the code goes away before that, then the computer shrugs it off.\n
     </string>
    <string name="SpeedCommand"> Current speed.\n
</string>

    <string name="ActualEnginePercentTorqueCommand">ActualEnginePercentTorqueCommand </string>
    <string name="CommandedEGRCommand">CommandedEGRCommand</string>
    <string name="CommandedEvaporativePurgeCommand">CommandedEvaporativePurgeCommand </string>
    <string name="DriverDemandEnginePercentTorqueCommand">DriverDemandEnginePercentTorqueCommand</string>
    <string name="EGRErrorCommand">EGRErrorCommand</string>
    <string name="EngineReferenceTorqueCommand">EngineReferenceTorqueCommand</string>
    <string name="EthanolPercentageCommand">EthanolPercentageCommand </string>
    <string name="HybridBatteryPackRemainingLifeCommand">HybridBatteryPackRemainingLifeCommand</string>
    
    
    
</resources>
